(
"ai_sub_version": "1.11.0",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 3,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
【LOG IN】
GAME START
Koseki Bijou 3D Live 2025
NOW LORDING...
NOW LOADING...
NEW GAME
EXIT
Are you ready?
Let's have a game!
ロボ子さん
Robocosan
IRyS
一伊那爾栖
Ninomae Ina'nis
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
轟はじめ
Todoroki Hajime
ラプラス・ダークネス
La+ Darknesss
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
Oh!
Alright!
Yeah, let's go!
Huh?
Ugh...
Mmm...
WHAT THE PEE!
Dang it!
Oh, man...
Oh, what's going on?
Where... where am I?
No way! Did I get sucked into the game world?
Oh, what... what do I do?
Hello?
Oh, why are there so many eyes on me?
They're not saying anything.
Oh, I have to get back!
Today is such an important day,
I can't get stuck in here!
Oh, what should I do?
I guess I have to figure this out on my own. Um...
Whoa, there's so many people looking at me.
Are those Pebbles? Hello?
Are you expecting me to do something?
Maybe I should sing and dance,
because this looks like a stage.
Maybe...
Maybe that'll be how I get out.
Okay, okay, I got it then.
I'm gonna sing and dance a song right now!
Here we go!
This game!
This game / Lyrics: 涼内亜希 / Music: 若林充
This game / Lyrics: Aki Suzuuchi / Music: Mitsuru Wakabayashi
廻り続ける
Rotating around
愚か者に割り当てられた
Assigned to the fools
平穏を演じる
Acting out peacefulness
感情から始まった地獄
The hell that started from emotions
遊び半分で神々が導いた
Guided by gods in half-play
盤上の世界
The world on the board
No no no game no life
ぬるい平穏をバッサリ切り捨てて
Cutting off the lukewarm peace
栄光の階段に存在刻むんだ
Carving my existence into the stairs of glory
目に映るのは完全勝利の運命
What I see is the destiny of complete victory
何もかも計算どおり
Everything is just as calculated
変えてやる 止まらない空白で
I'll change it with the unstoppable blank space
We are Maverick 救済なんていらない
We are Maverick, no need for salvation
どんな理不尽襲おうとも
No matter what unreasonableness attacks
勝てばいいだけの話だ
It's just a matter of winning
駆け引きと才能が無敗誘う
Strategy and talent invite invincibility
生まれ落ちた日に触れた楽しさを
The fun I felt on the day I was born
思い出していくんだ
I'm starting to remember it
自分だけは自分信じてる
I believe in myself, at least
心の底に潜む
Hidden at the bottom of the heart
闇より強い相手はいない
There is no opponent stronger than darkness
挫けぬ限りに敗北はありえない
As long as I don't give up, defeat is impossible
上辺の個性で安心と引き換えに
Exchanging peace for a superficial personality
プライド殺すな
Don't kill your pride
No no no sense of life
野蛮な雑音をキッパリ蹴飛ばして
Kicking away the barbaric noise
誰より純粋な声上げるんだ
Raising a voice purer than anyone's
戦うことはきっと間違いじゃない
Fighting is surely not a mistake
手応えが教えてくれた
The response taught me that
全て失っても勝ち残れ
Even if I lose everything, survive and win
We are Maverick 常識なんていらない
We are Maverick, no need for common sense
前倣え向かう先に
At the destination everyone follows
待ってるのは退屈な一辺倒
What's waiting is a boring monotony
つまらない 挑んでやる
How boring, I'll challenge it
生まれ落ちた日の命を誇りにして
Taking pride in the life from the day I was born
楽しむんだ
Enjoy it
自分だけの道を最後まで
Follow my own path until the end
迷わない 選ばれし者の自惚れでも
No hesitation, even if it's the conceit of the chosen one
誇らしく生き抜くための
To live through proudly
方法を一つしか知らないから
Because I only know one way
We are Maverick 救済なんていらない
We are Maverick, no need for salvation
どんな理不尽襲おうとも
No matter what unreasonableness attacks
勝てばいいだけの話だ
It's just a matter of winning
駆け引きと才能が無敗誘う
Strategy and talent invite invincibility
生まれ落ちた日に触れた楽しさを
The fun I felt on the day I was born
思い出していくんだ
I'm starting to remember it
楽しむんだ
Enjoy it
この世界手にして笑うんだ
Taking this world in hand and laughing
We are Maverick 最強の空っぽゲーマー
We are Maverick, the strongest empty gamers
空白ならば何者にもなれる
If it's blank, I can become anything
自分だけは自分信じてる
I believe in myself, at least
Yeah!
How was that? That was the best performance ever, right?
Hey over there!
You liked it, right? Hey!
With this I should be able to get back to my own world.
Alright, I'm ready! Beam me up Pebbles!
Ah! Ah! Why isn't it working?
No!
The coins!
Where are you going?
Dang it.
Well, according to video game logic, this must mean
I must now go on an epic quest to find the coins or something.
But I don't have time for that!
I need the coins back to get home! No!
Huh? Huh?
Oh, what's this?
Uh, I mean, I came out through there, so maybe
this will take me, you know, on my next step of my quest?
Well, better than being stuck here. So...
Let's go!
Ah! No... uh...
Huh? Huh? I'm not back in my world?
え、ここどこ？
Wait, where am I?
待ってたよ、ビブー。
I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
Robocosan Joins the Battle! Fighting Game Battle
Eh? Eh? Roboco-senpai?
探しているのは...これ？
Is this what you're looking for?
Ah! Coin, the coin!
MISSION: Reclaim the scattered coins from each stage's Game Master!
これがないと元の世界に戻れないんでしょ？
You can't get back to your original world without this, right?
でもそうはさせない。
But I won't let that happen.
ゲームマスターである僕たちから全て取り戻せるかな？
Can you take them all back from us Game Masters?
Eh? Honto? I don't know... Eh? Uh... Ah!
Eh? Really? I don't know... Eh? Uh... Ah!
と、とにかくこのコインが欲しければ...
Anyway, if you want this coin...
僕と...勝負だ！
you'll have to... battle me!
A match?
そう、yes! 格闘ゲームで勝負だ！
Right, yes! Let's battle in a fighting game!
Alright, I won't lose! Let's go!
リモコン Lyrics, Music: じーざす
Remote Control Lyrics, Music: Jesus-P
これが私をリモートで
This is the machine that
コントロールする機械です
controls me remotely
少し歪な形しておりますが
It's a bit of an odd shape,
使えます
but it works
伝わる 伝わる sit down please
Communicating, communicating, sit down please
フィードバックに体預けて
Surrender your body to the feedback
めぐる めぐる turn around
Going 'round and 'round, turn around
うなりを上げて 朦朧状態
Raising a roar into a hazy state
踊る 踊る dancing night
Dancing, dancing, dancing night
マッシュアップでもれなくアガる
Getting pumped up with a mashup
Go-way を上げて singing now
Go-way, raise it up, singing now
あの子よりも上手く歌いたい
I want to sing better than that girl
これが僕をリモートで
This is the machine that
操縦できる機械です
can operate me remotely
説明書は紛失しておりますが
The manual is lost,
使えます
but it works
カラカった顔
Your teased face
見てみたい　いつもの顔
I want to see your usual face
余裕でしょう
It's a breeze, right?
今日はかなり本気だぜ　ほら
I'm pretty serious today, look
すぐキメて
Do it quickly
座る座る　シッダウン・プリーズ
Sit, sit, sit down please
トーク枠を頭に挿して
Sticking a talk bubble on my head
回る回る　カインダ
Turning, turning, kinda...
ちょっと待って　スタンバイ状態で
Wait a second, in standby mode
踊る踊る　ダンシン・ナイト
Dancing, dancing, dancing night
ジャスト・フィットな　リズムを出して
Give it a rhythm that fits just right
唸り上げる　シンギン・ナウ
Roaring out, singing now
アイツよりも高く歌っていたい
I want to sing higher than that guy
惚れた腫れたの七色ザムライ
In love or infatuated, a rainbow samurai
洗いざらい主張する存在
An existence that asserts everything
思い違いが透けてるアンバイ
A state where misunderstandings are transparent
怖いくらいの若輩感情だい
It's a frighteningly immature feeling
気にしないのがあなたのポリシー
Not caring is your policy
悩んでいてもお腹は減るし
Even if I'm worried, I still get hungry
なんだかんだで世間はヘルシー
One way or another, the world is healthy
お気を確かにぬるま湯ダンス
Keep your wits about you, lukewarm dance
もうちょっとで隙間も埋まるのに
Just a little more and the gap will be filled
うまみの身
Body of umami
どうやっても上手くいかねえ
No matter what I do, it doesn't go well
ああ　もう時間が足りない
Ah, I'm out of time
ドゥワドゥワ　シッダウン・プリーズ
Doo-wah doo-wah, sit down please
膝を曲げて体溶けていく
Bend your knees, your body is melting
メグルメグル　ターン・アラウンド
Turning, turning, turn around
唸り上げてもスタンバイ状態で
Even if I roar out, in standby mode
踊る踊る　ダンシン・ナイト
Dancing, dancing, dancing night
マッシュアップで漏れなく上がる
Mash up, rising without fail
声を上げて　シンギン・ナウ
Shout out, singing now
あの子みたいな瞳になりたい
I want to have eyes like that girl's
座る座る　シッダウン・プリーズ
Sit, sit, sit down please
メグルメグル　ターン・アラウンド
Turning, turning, turn around
踊る踊る　ダンシン・ナイト
Dancing, dancing, dancing night
声を上げて　シンギン・ナウ
Shout out, singing now
あの子みたいな瞳になりたい
I want to have eyes like that girl's
Wahoo!
I win!
Noooo!
A coin!
Yay!
I got a coin!
Go to the next stage.
But, be careful.
次のゲームマスターは、僕のようにはいかないぞ。
The next game master won't be as easy as I was.
No easy.
大丈夫だよ！
It's okay!
Bibooだから！
Because I'm Biboo!
ありがとう先輩！
Thanks, Senpai!
じゃあ、バイバイ！
See ya! Bye bye!
Hahahaha!
We've been waiting for you, Biboo!
IRyS, Ninomae Ina'nis Joins the Battle!
Huh?
IRyS?
Ina?
I'm assuming this
is what you're looking for, right?
Yes, yes! I need that!
Give me that! Give it!
We won't just hand it over.
You'll have to race us for it.
Eh?
Give it!
Where are you putting that?
I'm putting that back in my pocket.
If you want it, you have to beat us.
Are you ready to battle?
Fine!
I'll be cool too, watch this.
Oh hey, I'm Wolo-biza!
Heh!
No one can stop us tonight
No one can stop us shine
Save me, I think I'm freezing up,
so cold inside
But I'm a quiet blue look at you
Save me, I need a guiding touch
in these dark times
Follow the touch of sheen
Inside the maze of your heart,
I'm the soul that strayed
Inside the maze baby look at me,
you're not fine
Oh can't you see that I can be refined?
Your heart is super hot right now
It's time to be your Diamond Girlfriend
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
let them light the way
Precious Girlfriend go go go!
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakening so
Break it all, break it all, break it all
The Diamond Girlfriend!
Yeah you gotta go hit
beat on my door
巻き散らすのオーブ、凛々のスパークル
Spreading out the orbs, the dignified sparkles
Just hit it and wheel it,
make the sound ぱちり
make the sound 'snap'
まぶしすぎるメイクアップ、クラムジャム
A makeup that's way too dazzling, Clam Jam!
Trust me,
your weary eyes betray what you've tried to hide
密かな愛しを伝わり
A secret love is being conveyed
Trust me,
I'll never shy away from your dark side
道は導きにハイペース
The path is high-paced towards guidance
Under the pressure and fires
these ashes reborn
You're reborn
Let me show you who I really am
In the name of love I'll be a gem
Your heart is super hot right now
It's time to be your Diamond Girlfriend
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
let them light the way
Precious Girlfriend go go go!
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakening so
Break it all, break it all, break it all
Now see us, your atomic symbol
ぐるぐる回る、真っ赤になるまで WIMBO
Spinning around, until it turns deep red, WIMBO
愛が足りないとが闇が深いほど
The more you lack love, the deeper the darkness is
タッチ・ウェブ・ジャムあつかお I'm a jeweler
Touch, web, jam, let's play it, I'm a jeweler
さぁ踊りなさい！
Now, dance!
Shine on, shine bright,
like my flame
Until it all melts away
Are you ready?!
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
let them light the way
Precious Girlfriend go go go!
Overheating love machine burning
Hot, hot, hot, hot, I'm the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakening so
Break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can stop my shine tonight
No one can stop my shine!
やったー！ウフフ！ウフフ！
Yay! Woohoo! Woohoo!
Are you guys okay?
Yeah.
Did I hit you hard?
Goddamn it! Oh yeah!
I got the coin! I'm the winner! I win!
Whoa!
Oh! What is that?
Portal? Oh a portal!
By the way, where did the coin come from, IRyS?
Uh, it...
Don't worry about it!
It came from my Nephilim pocket!
Oh no! Goodbye!
Ah! The world is spinning! Whoa!
Ugh... I'm dizzy...
Huh? Is this the puzzle stage?
Hey! I'm ready for my next challenge now!
Hey, come out! Hey!
は？
Huh?
There's no Game Master this time?
Eh... Well, I guess I could use a break or something then.
Hmm, maybe I'll dance and sing by myself, you know, as a refresher.
Yeah, so I'll be ready for the next challenge!
This is a puzzle stage, so it does remind me of a certain song.
Hey, everyone over there! You want to hear it too, right?
Yeah!
Okay! They didn't say anything, I'm just talking to myself.
Well, all right then! Let's dance!
Tetris!
ドシテドシテ　引いてしまうの
Why, oh why, do I end up pulling back?
トシンデトシンデ　死んでしまうアト
Dashing and dashing, after I die
ゴシンデトシンデ　インキしましょうか
Shall we play a game of mistake and dash?
悪くない
Not bad
キョーミネソク　いい派手感度
Interest immediately sparks a flashy feel
ジョビネ薬　タベパド
Jovine medicine, tabepado
チョーヒデフル　見つめ安吾か
Staring intensely like Ango?
金による
It's all about the money
ジョシキデフル　インポルタント
Common sense is important
ホチキステフル　インクバンド
Stapler full of ink band
ソシンデフル　システムコントロール
Reviving the system control
和が映える
Harmony shines through
ドシテスグ　見てしまうの
Why do I look right away?
ドシテスグ　言ってしまうの
Why do I say it right away?
ドシテスグ　怖れちゃうかな
Why do I get scared so soon?
キンミライ的　カカタタン
Near-future style, kaka-tatan
ショッピングモール的　ゲンダイコン
Shopping mall style, modern complex
ショウインドウ的　カカタタン
Show window style, kaka-tatan
文字ホール的　ケェヒリピンボール
Character hole style, K-hill pinball
和をむさぼり　100ポンド素足
Indulging in harmony, 100 pound bare feet
予定突き　揺する嘘を
Poking at plans, shaking up the lies
テテテテテテテテテトリス
Te-te-te-te-te-te-te-te-Tetris
ドシテコンナメニ　ニニニ
Why has it come to this? Ni-ni-ni
キョーミがないことほど
The less interest I have,
ホンキじゃないもの全部
all the things I'm not serious about,
あとまわしで
I'll put them off for later.
シテルコトは　シランプリ
Pretending not to notice what I'm doing,
私は　オワッテイル
I'm already finished.
ハズカシイ　カクシテル
Embarrassing secrets I'm hiding,
ヤツラのキオク　ケサセテ
make them erase those memories.
メイワクカケテ　ゴメンテバネ
I'm sorry for causing trouble,
誰かタスケテ
someone please help me.
モシンデトスグ　光っちゃうの
Immediately shining with blind faith,
ドシンデトスグ　光っちゃうの
immediately shining with a crash,
知りたくない　知りたくない　知りたくない
I don't want to know, don't want to know, don't want to know
モミミデトスグ　光っちゃうぞ
Immediately shining in my ears,
ジョキデフル　至るまで
until it reaches a clean state,
行きたくない　行きたくない　行きたくない
I don't want to go, don't want to go, don't want to go
バイバイ
Bye-bye
シンジキ　キュウセンポウル
Shin-jiki, nine thousand poles
ナイチンゲールナ　ハイシンゲーム
Nightingale streaming game
メシホカノ　メイシン
Food other than superstition,
ジャキンポウルデ　チヂラハイボウル
shrunken highball with an evil pole
オデンビョコ　タプヨカショクジツキ
Oden-byoko, tapyoka meal plan
早く生きて
live quickly,
テテテテテテテテテリョーカ
Te-te-te-te-te-te-te-te-ryoka
アンセシュウ　ジジジ
Peaceful training, ji-ji-ji
嘘とか本当とか
Whether it's lies or truth,
いそがしくて眠れない　今日も
I'm so busy I can't sleep, even today.
誰が早く　殴ってきて
Someone, please punch me quickly
停止させてくれよ
and make me stop.
人生キャンセル　キャンセル界隈
Life cancel, cancel circle,
ぼんやりとした不安
a vague sense of anxiety.
私のせい　私が悪いよ
It's my fault, I'm the one to blame,
そうだよ
that's right.
キョーミが出て　本気でやっても
Even if I get interested and try my best,
全部空回りで
it's all in vain,
知らないくせに　嘘つき私は
acting like I know when I don't, I'm a liar,
終わっている
I'm already finished.
ハズカシイ　カクシテル
Embarrassing secrets I'm hiding,
ヤツラのキオク　ケサセテ
make them erase those memories.
メイワクカケテ　ゴメンテバネ
I'm sorry for causing trouble,
誰かタスケテ
someone please help me.
メイワクカケテ　ゴメンテバネ
I'm sorry for causing trouble,
誰かヨロシテ
someone please forgive me.
Whoa! Ah! Woah, dizzy, dizzy...
Whoa, that scared me! I don't know, this game's bugged, man!
Hey, someone report these bugs, dang it!
Cubes start popping out and everything...
Who designed this? I need to meet the devs. Hey, devs!
This game is malfunctioning. But I don't have time for that.
I gotta find the coins!
え？　あー
Eh? Oh...
I guess that's my cue to leave. Okay, next stage!
Let's charge up! Helicopter, helicopter!
Ohhhhhhh!
Oof! I gotta work on that landing. Oh?
Wow! What a cute stage! Kawaii!
ホ、ホ、ホ、ホ、ホ、ホ、ホ、ホ！
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho!
おー、どうもどうも待ってましたよ、ビブー！
Oh, hello there, I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Shirakami Fubuki Joins the Battle!
Crane Game Battle
フブキ先輩！
Fubuki-senpai!
ビブーはこれが欲しいんだよね？
Biboo, you want this, don't you?
可愛い！欲しい、欲しい！
Cute! I want it, I want it!
ならば白上と勝負だ！
Then it's a battle with Shirakami!
白上のクレーンゲームから果たして逃げられるかな？
I wonder if you can escape from Shirakami's crane game?
え？　うーん...　Okay then!
Eh? Mmm... Okay then!
負けないよ！
I won't lose!
ふん！
Hum!
LONELY ROLLING STAR
Lyrics, Music: NAMCO (Yuu Miyake)
ひだまり
Sunny spot
さんさん
Brightly shining
心は
My heart...
晴れ模様
...is clear and sunny.
二つの
These two...
瞳は
...eyes...
ひまわり
...are sunflowers...
の種のよう
...like the seeds within.
語らい
Talking
重なり
Overlapping
塊
A mass
絡まり
Tangled
一緒に
Being together...
いる事
...with you...
絶対
...is definitely...
必然
...inevitable.
でもあなた大事な
But you, while painting...
夢を描く
...your precious dreams.
終わるまではずっと
Until it's finished, I'll be...
ここで待ってるよ
...waiting here forever.
マジで
Seriously.
Lonely Rolling Star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't stop rolling, okay?
Lonely Rolling Star
さあ前を向いて
Come on, look forward...
行こう
...and go.
星空
The starry sky
きらきら
Twinkling bright
金平糖
Just like stars...
のよう
...of sugar candy.
甘くて
A sweet...
切ない
...and painful...
思いが
...feeling...
つのるの
...grows stronger.
抱きしめた想いは
The feelings I held close...
夜空を舞い
...dance through the night sky.
急降下して
Diving down...
あなたの元へ
...straight towards you.
届くかな
Will it reach you?
Lonely Rolling Star
あきらめないでね
Don't give up, okay?
Lonely Rolling Star
たまには電話して
Give me a call sometimes.
Lonely Rolling Star
会いたい夜はすぐ
In a night I long to see you...
Lonely Rolling Star
ああため息が一つ
Ah, another sigh...
こぼれる
...spills out.
Lonely Rolling Star
立ち止まらないでね
Don't stop rolling, okay?
Lonely Rolling Star
思い出してね
Remember me, okay?
Lonely Rolling Star
待っていられない
I can't wait any longer.
最後まであの場所で
Until the end, let's meet...
待ち合わせをしよう
...at that special place.
イェーイ！勝った！勝った！
Yay! I won! I won!
あれは使っちゃった、Biboo...
You used that thing, Biboo...
アヘヘ、ボコボコにされちゃったよ〜
Ahehe, I got beaten to a pulp~
コインが〜！イェーイ！
The coin~! Yay!
You got the coin! Yay!
I'm the winner!
可愛いから許して！
Forgive me because I'm cute!
しょうがない、許す。可愛いからね！
I have no choice but to forgive you. Because you're cute!
じゃ、次の世界へ、Biboo!
Now, to the next world, Biboo!
かかってくるがいい！
Come at me!
おっけー、じゃ、先輩、おねがい！
Okay, then, Senpai, please!
はーい、いくぞー！レッツゴー、コセキ！
Alright, let's go! Let's go, Koseki!
Todoroki Hajime Joins the Battle!
Rhythm Dance Battle
Hajime? What?!
これが欲しければ、拙者と勝負だ！
If you want this, you'll have to face me!
My coin!
うー、はじめのダンスについて来られるかな？
Ooh, I wonder if you can keep up with Hajime's dancing?
Dance? Hmm...
Okay! Let's dance together!
みんなー！チルノのさんすうきょうしつはじまるよー！
Everyone! Cirno's math class is starting!
あたいみたいな天才目指して、がんばっていってね！
Aim for a genius like me and do your best!
がんばっていってね！
Do your best!
キラキラダイアモンド
Kira kira diamond
輝く星のように
Shining like a star
栄光 志望校 なんとかして入ろう
Honor, dream school, I'll get in somehow
天才 秀才 トップ目指して GO GO!
Genius, prodigy, aiming for the top, GO GO!
バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ バーカ...
Dummy, dummy, dummy, dummy, dummy, dummy...
ちょっと、バカじゃないもん！
Hey, I'm not a dummy!
「バカ」っていうほうがバカなのよ！
The one who says 'dummy' is the dummy!
何よ、うるさいわね！このバカ！
What was that? You're annoying! You dummy!
紅魔館からバスが出て
A bus left from the Scarlet Devil Mansion
始めに三人乗りました
At first, three people were on board
白玉楼で一人降りて
One person got off at Hakugyokurou
半人だけ乗りました
Then half a person got on board
八雲さんちで一人降りて
One person got off at Yakumo's place
二人降りて
Two people got off
結局乗客合計何人だ？
So, how many passengers total?
答えは 答えは 0人 0人
The answer is, the answer is 0! 0!
なぜなら なぜなら それは
Because, because, that is...
幻想郷にバス無い
There are no buses in Gensokyo!
山落ち 意味など無いわ
Climax and resolution are meaningless
キャラクター立てばいいのよ
Characters just need to stand out
元気があればなんでも
If you have energy, you can do anything!
① ② ⑨!
1, 2, 9!
くるくる時計の針
Spinning round, hands of the clock
ぐるぐる頭まわる
Spinning round, my head's spinning
だって つぶら目玉 二つしかないのに
I mean, even though I only have two round eyes
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかん
Having three hands is all Greek to me
次々問題出る
The questions keep coming
まだまだ授業続く
The class still goes on
凍る部屋の中 ひんやりした温度も
Inside the frozen room, even the chilly air
時間も気にせず ゆっくりしていってね！
Without worrying about time, just take it easy!
だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ！
I'm telling you, I'm not a dummy!
いい加減にしないと 凍結するわよ
If you don't stop, I'll freeze you!
そして粉々になって死ねばいいのよ！
Then you can just break into pieces and die!
霊夢んとこの百万延の
Reimu's one-million-yen worth of...
壺を誰かが割っちゃった
Someone broke her jar!
永遠亭のえーりんが
Eirin from Eientei
弁償に来ましたよ
She came to pay the reparations
知らんぷりのイタズラでね
Pretending not to know, with a prank
結局賠償金額いくら？
So, how much is the compensation in the end?
答えは 答えは 0円 0円 なぜなら なぜなら それは
The answer is, the answer is 0 yen! 0 yen! Because, because, that is...
そんな壺あるわけない
There's no way such a jar exists!
常識超えたところに
In a place beyond common sense
世界の真理がある
The truth of the world lies there
秘密の数字目指して
Aiming for the secret numbers
① ② ⑨!
1, 2, 9!
ヘラヘラニヤけながら
While grinning and smirking
ゲラゲラ笑いながら
While laughing and cackling
うっざー！
So annoying!
因幡ウサギ 可愛げもないのに
新参の徒どもは ホイホイホイ
Inaba rabbits, not even cute,
yet the newcomers flock to them like flies.
再生百万回 もれなく愚民なんて
どういうことなのよ
A million views, and they're all idiots?
What's that about?
どちらかって言うなら サーバー管理も
お疲れさんってとこね
If anything, I should say
good job on the server management.
「わかった！ アタイがあまりにも天才だから
嫉妬してるんでしょ♪」
"I get it! You're just jealous
because I'm such a genius, right?♪"
「ほんと、しょうがないわね！
せっかくお近づきになれたんだから アタイの天才の秘訣を…」
"Seriously, I have no choice!
Since we've gotten close, I'll let you in on the secret of my genius..."
「ちょっとだけ教えてあげてもいいわよ！」
"I could teach you just a little bit!"
あたいのあたいのあたいのあたいの...
I am, I am, I am, I am...
英知を集めて集めて集めて集めて束ねても
Even if you gather, gather, gather all the wisdom together...
あたいのあたいの丈夫な頭に
To my, my... strong head,
集まれ集まれ集まれ集まれ叶わない
Gather, gather, gather... it's no match.
あめちゃんあめちゃんあめちゃんあめちゃん食べたら
If I eat, eat, eat, eat... candy,
あの子のあの子のあの子のあの子の手をひねる
I'll twist that kid's hand like it's easy as pie.
あたいはあたいはあたいはあたいは完璧
I am, I am, I am, I am... perfect.
いわゆるいわゆるいわゆるいわゆるパーフェクト
So to speak, I am... perfect.
ひゃ～くおくじゅうまんバッチリ！
Ten billion, perfectly!
山落ち意味など無いわ
There's no need for a climax or a point.
キャラクター立てばいいのよ
As long as the character is established.
元気があれば何でも
If you have energy, you can do anything.
１、２、９！
One, two, nine!
ぐるぐる時計の針
Round and round, the clock hands,
ぐるぐる頭まわる
Round and round, my head spins.
だってつぶら目玉
Because despite my round eyes,
二つしかないのに
I only have two,
三本の針なんてちんぷんかんぷん
So three clock hands are just gibberish to me.
次々問題出る
Problems come out one after another,
まだまだ授業続く
The class continues on and on.
凍る部屋の中 ひやりとした温度も時間も
気にせずゆっくりしていってね！
In the freezing room, don't worry about the chilly
temperature or time, and just take it easy!
バーカ、バーカ！
Stupid, stupid!
もうバカでいいわよ知らない！
Fine, call me stupid! I don't care!
おー、あたいのダンスについてこれるなんて、
なかなかやるな！
Oh, keeping up with my dance?
You're pretty good!
はー！ よし、コインをよこせ！
Hah! Alright, hand over the coin!
イエーイ！ アイ・ガット・ア・コイン！
Yay! I got a coin!
じゃ、はじめ！ サンキュー・フォー・ダンシング・ウィズ・ミー！
めっちゃ楽しかった！
Then, Hajime! Thank you for dancing with me!
It was so much fun!
めっちゃ楽しかった！ ありがとう！
It was so much fun! Thank you!
テイク・ケア！ じゃ、アイ・マスト・ゴー！
うわ、オッケー！
Take care! Then, I must go!
Whoa, okay!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ふー、あー...
Phew, ah...
おー、アイム・ヒア・オールレディ。オッケー、アイ・シー。
Oh, I'm here already. Okay, I see.
ワオ、ワッツ・ネクスト・ゼン？ ザ・レスト・イズ...
アイ・カウント、ワン、ツー。ツー・チャレンジズ・レフト、アイ・シンク。フォー・ツー・コインズ。
Wow, what's next then? The rest is...
I count, one, two. Two challenges left, I think. For two coins.
待っていたぞ、ビブー！
We've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Amane Kanata / La+ Darknesss Joins the Battle!
え、かなた先輩？ ラプラス？
ホワット・アー・ユー・ドゥーイング・ヒア？
Eh, Kanata-senpai? La+?
What are you doing here?
これが欲しければ、我々と勝負だ！
If you want this, then battle us!
オー、マイ・コイン！
Oh, my coin!
勝負だ！ 迫り来るゾンビを全部倒すことができるかな？
It's a challenge! I wonder if you can
defeat all the approaching zombies?
オー、ウェル、じゃ、私は... 死なない！
Oh well, then, I... won't die!
Run away, run away, run away now
Time to put the weapons down
Nowhere to go, nowhere to go, nowhere
No road is left to run
I was born, I was born with horns
Demons come to shake me up
Bring it on, bring it on, bring it on
'Cause we haven't had enough
Don't give up the fight
Make it out alive
Step inside the final war
Don't give up the fight
Make it out alive
It's time I won't let you down
We're gonna make it out alive now
Tonight, tonight, tonight
I'm screaming on the inside
I lost my heart, I lost my heart, I lost my heart
Already for this fight
Gotta have faith, gotta have faith beyond the unknown
It's the only way to live
Ready to go, ready to go, ready to go
Somewhere I've never been
What's keeping us down for...
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now
Whoa, whoa
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn now
Whoa, whoa
We're gonna make it out
Make it out alive
Set this world on fire now
Whoa, whoa
Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn now
Whoa, whoa
We're gonna make it out alive
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, make it out, make it out
We're gonna make it out alive
全部倒すなんて、すげーじゃん！
Wiping them all out was awesome!
あ、終わった？
Ah, it's over?
よーし、コインをやろう！
Alright, let's toss a coin!
じゃ、みんな、ありがとね。
Well, thanks everyone.
おーい、ハッピーバースデー！
Hey, Happy Birthday!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you very much!
オーケー！
Okay!
じゃあ！
Bye!
さよならー！
Goodbye!
Ah, nice landing. Yeah.
Huh?
Oh, it's the first stage.
Maybe this is like a progress check sort of thing? Let's see... let's see where I'm at, huh?
Oh! I'm missing one more coin!
But where could it be?
Is anyone here to give me another game or something?
Hello? Hello?
Maybe this is like the safe zone where I can like take a break and recover.
That's a good idea.
You know, I'm feeling kinda tired, and all these songs have been so Biboo-intensely intense.
Let's, let's take a break.
I'll just... a nap over here. I'll wake up in just... whatever, once I'm done.
Just give me like five minutes, okay? Just five minutes.
Oyasumiyuu.
Goodnighty-yuu.
You know... oyasumi. See ya, see ya.
You know... good night. See ya, see ya.
Flow
Lyrics: Kathryn Cwynar, Natsuko Ishikawa
Music: Masayoshi Soken
Well come and well met,
my brave little spark.
How long you've wandered,
burned bright as a star.
Oh...
Oh, I have awaited you patiently all this time
all this time
Past every fate
Now sing with me once more, share of your life
Far greater than memory, its loss and love words cannot hold
Boundless the tale overflows
And carries your light out to sea
Remember the rain, near and far beloved
Each drop a blessing from heavens above
And how as time flowed on those waters became one
Streams, rivers and lakes
Reaching for the horizon and far beyond
They carry onward however changed with each brief reflection, by setting sun
By storm's wake
Til welcomed home to gentle sea
Sinking deeper and deeper in calm embrace
Loving tides sweep in and bear you down
Should you meet a soul rising surface-ways
With your unbeating heart, wish them well
Deep, dark, far away, I have heard your voice, weighed your every choice
Deep, dark, far away,
I have heard your voice, weighed your every choice
Now our hands join round the meaning you sought
Now our hands join round
the meaning you sought
I'll catch your tears, quench your fears with joy til you near the shore
I'll catch your tears,
quench your fears
with joy til you near the shore
Where in time, all shall as hope be reborn, and...
Where in time, all shall as hope be reborn, ad
Hush, love, close your eyes, and in sleep abide
Hush, love, close your eyes,
and in sleep abide
As sun's distant light echoes down to dreams below
As sun's distant light,
echoes down to dreams below
Know you will wake, on winds rise again
For this journey's end is but one step forward to tomorrow
Ugh...
Wha...
what a good dream!
Alright, let's check our progress then.
Hmm, we're still missing one coin.
Where could it be?
Ah! Again!
What's happening?!
What the beeb?!
I've been waiting for you,
Bijou.
Fake Biboo Joins the Battle!
You... You're...
I'm you.
Me? You mean...
...my last opponent is me?
Exactly.
Me.
You.
Your biggest enemy,
your biggest obstacle,
yourself.
No...
You've done well at making it this far, Bijou.
But I don't intend to hold back.
Then, I won't either.
This stage is too important for me to give up now!
I feel like I'm losing hope
In my body and my soul
And the sky,
it looks so ominous
And as time comes to a halt
Silence starts to overflow
My cries
are inconspicuous
Tell me God, are
you punishing me?
Is this the price I'm paying
for my past mistakes?
This
is my redemption song
I need you more than ever right now
Can you hear me now?
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
I wish that someway, somehow
That I could save every one of us
But the truth is that I'm only one girl
Maybe if I keep believing
My dreams will come to life
Come to life
溢れる色彩
Overflowing colors
零れる命
Spilling life
風は今も遠く
The wind is still far away
剥がれる錆びと
With the peeling rust
蠢く刃
And the writhing blades
逃げ場いつも森に
The place to escape is always in the forest
これが僕の呪い
This is my curse
約束殺す痛みが
The pain that kills the promise
君の
Your
君の願い
Your wish
最後の夢を捨てた
I threw away the last dream
償いだけど
It's an atonement, but
そう僕らは今
Yes, we are now
ああ無価値でも叫ぶ
Ah, even if worthless, we shout
この汚れた世界の愛
The love of this filthy world
そう僕らは今
Yes, we are now
ああ無意味でも願う
Ah, even if meaningless, we pray
ただ君との時間を
Just the time with you
溺れた意識は
The drowned consciousness
優しいまま
While still being kind
消えて
Fade away
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
Yes, we are now
あぁ無意味でも願う
Ah, even if it's meaningless, I pray
ただ君との未来を
Only for a future with you
Still, we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
Yes, we are now
I hope that someday,
あぁ無意味でも願う
Ah, even if it's meaningless, I pray
That I could save every one of us
ただ君との時間を
Only for a time with you
祈り歌を　得られずとも
Even if my prayer song is never heard
My dreams will come to life
僕は
I...
Impressive.
Yes! The coin!
Oh, you're still alive. Oh.
You, who have defeated all the game masters, shall be rewarded.
Huh? What... what is this?
Now, show this to everyone.
Yeah! Hey thanks, but...
...there can only be one! Hah!
Hello everyone! We have made it to the final stage!
You didn't think I collected all those coins and played all those games for nothing, did you?
No, because I'm cashing it in with all of these coins we have unlocked...
...my new original song! Woohoo!
And guess what? The video's gonna come out right after this. Good job everyone!
And I'm gonna perform it to you right now! Are you ready?
Let's go out with a bang! ROCKIN!
Bibou's here to play
Yeah, uh-huh
Uh, uh
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let's take a chance, game on, and shoot my shot
Log in, get good, you mad?
Let's go talk beep, get hit,
clean sweep
Now you know what's up, hit 'em with a 1-2-3 Bibou-Bibou
Come and test your luck, yeah we comin' in clutch Bibou-Bibou
Skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one-shot Bibou-Bibou
Come and help me fight, get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss! ROCKIN!
Bububa bubububa bubububa bubububa
Bububa bubububa bububa bambam ba
Bububa wawa wah bububu bububu bububu ba
Level up we go onwards
Aiming for another win
A diamond in the rough, it's kinda tough
You gotta keep on rollin'
The grind goes on and on, no breaks
Seal the cracks with a few Band-Aids
I'll try over and over and over again
Just one more round please?
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo-Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo-Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one shot, Biboo-Biboo
Come and help me fight
Get an up on those who's behind you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
ROCKIN'!
Lost in this game, I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity
I see the shape, I feel the space
It's set in stone, carve it into me
I just wanna be Bi-
-boo
Now you know what's up, hit 'em with a one-two-three
Biboo-Biboo, come and test your luck, yeah we're comin' in clutch
Biboo-Biboo, skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one shot
Biboo-Biboo, better hit quicksave 'cause Biboo's here to play!
Now you know what's up, hit 'em with a one-two-three
Biboo-Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah we're comin' in clutch, Biboo-Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one shot, Biboo-Biboo
Come and help me fight
Get an up on those who's behind you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
ROCKIN'!
Biboo-Biboo
Uh... Hello?
Um, I'm still here.
Ready to get teleported back to my world any... anytime now.
Mom, pick me up, I'm scared!
Hey! This wasn't part of the deal!
Hey!
No wait, what are you doing?
No! No! Nooo!
Hey! Listen to my song at least!
Okay? My song's coming out, listen to it!
ROCKIN'! Go, go!